CLERVILLE
THE END OF THE 1960s
NATIONAL BANK OF CLERVILLE
Calling all cars!
A black Jaguar has exited
the back of the bank!
He's turned left on to Via dei Platani.
This is Zebra-13, we're rapidly
approaching from Via del Corso.
Go! Faster!
He's turned on to Via delle Mimose.
Zebra-13, cut him off!
We have him trapped!
Stop!
Calling all cars!
The Jaguar has evaded us.
He's on Via delle Camelie.
We're outside the Embassy of Beglait,
we'll be there in a few seconds.
Suspect spotted on Via della Cascata.
We're on his tail!
Damn!
What the...
Gas!
Hold your breath.
That's him.
What the blazes, Inspector?
Diabolik.
A FEW MONTHS LATER
Minister, you don't mean to say
you won't be our guest tomorrow!
My dear Count,
your life is one endless holiday.
Lucky you.
But my duties dictate that
I return to Clerville.
Why not send Giorgio?
He's your deputy.
It's what he's there for.
To a meeting with the Prime Minister?
It wouldn't be appropriate.
It's a real shame.
I would've been happy to let you
try out my new Remington.
I had them attach
an extremely powerful viewfinder!
Pardon me.
Where's he off to?
Eva! Finally.
- Welcome.
- Thank you, Giorgio.
- How was your trip?
- Fine.
You look... stunning.
As always.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
- My pleasure.
- Come on, let me introduce you.
This way.
Mrs Duncan.
Lady Kant, I presume.
- Good evening, thank you for inviting me.
- Giorgio.
If all the girls in South Africa
are so beautiful,
I understand why you go there so often!
- I'm actually from Clerville.
- Ah!
Yes.
Eva spent many years in South Africa,
but now she has finally decided
to return home.
Giorgio!
Over here.
What are you doing?
Aren't you going to introduce me?
Lady Kant, Minister.
Enchanted.
Years ago, during a hunting expedition
in South Africa,
I met a Lord Kant.
Anthony, if I'm not mistaken.
A relation of yours?
- Perhaps your father?
- He was my husband.
Was?
Sadly, he died. Almost a year ago.
I'm most sorry.
He was a magnificent hunter.
May I ask how...
An accident.
On a big game hunting trip.
Good heavens, big game!
Thank goodness you men
only hunt roe deer.
I wouldn't be so sure about that, Emma.
- Your husband hunts some beasts
that are far more dangerous. - Indeed!
Minister, will you ever manage
to catch Diabolik?
Most certainly.
As Minister of Justice, my priority is
the safety of every citizen.
Yes, that criminal
has overstepped every mark.
He's spreading fear
throughout the State of Clerville.
But we are determined to stop him.
At any cost.
He sounds like a demon
more than a criminal.
Excuse me, are you talking about
someone who actually exists?
My dear Lady Kant,
I can only hope that you never come
face-to-face with him.
To meet Diabolik...
means meeting death.
Enough talking about that monster,
or tonight I'll have nightmares!
You're right, Mrs Duncan.
To apologise, I promise
that tomorrow I'll bring you
the youngest roe deer I've ever killed.
Already skinned and ready for the oven!
Forgive me for insisting,
but why don't you stay with me tonight?
I've got an enormous house all to myself.
It wouldn't be appropriate, Giorgio.
You're going a little fast.
At least let me give you a lift.
Thank you, but the hotel's nearby.
And I feel like a walk.
- Goodnight.
- Lady Kant?
- Yes.
Inspector Ginko. I need to have a word.
City of Clerville Police Force?
Don't tell me you came all this way
just for me?
I came because it's my duty to warn you.
Warn me?
Of what?
Diabolik.
So this mysterious criminal who
everyone is talking about really exists.
Of course.
Did you think it was an urban legend?
I'm certain he's planning a new heist.
Since you're telling me,
you think he's after the Pink Diamond.
Such a valuable gem would be
an irresistible temptation for Diabolik.
How could Diabolik know about
me and the Pink Diamond?
He manages to know everything.
Always.
Please, Inspector,
don't you start talking about Diabolik
as if he's a supernatural being!
No, no magic, Lady Kant.
He's just a man,
but an extraordinarily talented one.
As extraordinary as he may be,
I don't see how he could know about me.
I've only been here a few days.
I suspect he has a web of informers
working for him everywhere.
Here in Bellair. In South Africa.
You suspect?
Therefore, you're not certain.
We've carried out extensive investigations
in the criminal underworld,
but nobody ever talks.
Maybe because they all know
that to betray Diabolik...
means death.
Aren't you exaggerating, Inspector?
Believe me, Lady Kant,
if Diabolik intends
to steal the Pink Diamond,
your life may be in danger.
Do you want me to run back to South Africa
like a frightened little girl?
No.
I'll have some undercover agents
watch your hotel.
With maximum discretion,
no one will even notice them.
I see.
You intend to set a trap for him,
using me as the bait.
You are a most unique woman.
- If that's a compliment, thank you.
- No, an observation.
So, where will you be staying
in Clerville?
The Hotel Excelsior.
And the diamond?
It's on its way,
a special consignment from South Africa.
It'll be waiting for me
when I get to Clerville in two days.
Where will it be kept?
Officially, in the hotel manager's safe.
But it'll only hold an empty box.
The real diamond will be deposited
by the South African security guards
in another safe.
In my room.
But only the manager of the Excelsior
and I know this.
And now you, naturally.
Good.
Thank you for your time, Lady Kant.
One last thing.
Please don't tell anyone about
our conversation.
And should we meet again,
act as though it's the first time.
Why so much mystery?
No one knows the true face of Diabolik.
He could be anyone.
The waiter passing by.
The man behind me with the newspaper.
Or the man who has just come in.
Even one of my most trusted men.
You don't say?
He could be anyone.
Which is why I'd prefer if our meeting...
remained a secret.
In that case, Inspector...
it's my pleasure never to have met you.
And who gets to do it?
The manager made it absolutely clear,
this special task will be
Roberto's responsibility.
Why does he always get the easy jobs?!
What do you expect?
He's the manager's pet!
If the manager chose me to be
Lady Kant's personal concierge,
the reason is obvious.
Oh yeah, and what would that be?
Well, just take a look in the mirror.
- Listen to Mister Handsome!
- Our very own movie star!
You should be grateful to have a job!
This is only a stopgap job for me.
I've got much bigger plans.
I'm not like you two.
And what exactly does that mean,
"I'm not like you two"?
My dear fellows, unlike you,
I'm not going to die a concierge.
Sure, keep on dreaming!
STAFF ENTRANCE
- Goodnight, José.
- Goodnight.
If the manager chose me to be Lady Kant's
personal concierge, the reason is obvious.
If the manager chose me to be
Lady Kant's personal concierge,
the reason is obvious.
If the manager chose me to be Lady Kant's
personal concierge, the reason is obvious.
If the manager chose me to be
Lady Kant's personal concierge,
the reason is obvious.
If the manager chose me to be Lady Kant's
personal concierge, the reason is obvious.
If the manager chose me to be
Lady Kant's personal concierge,
the reason is obvious.
If the manager chose me to be Lady Kant's
personal concierge, the reason is obvious.
If the manager chose me to be
Lady Kant's personal concierge,
the reason is obvious.
If the manager chose me to be Lady Kant's
personal concierge, the reason is obvious.
If the manager chose me to be
Lady Kant's personal concierge,
the reason is obvious.
If the manager chose me to be Lady Kant's
personal concierge, the reason is obvious.
If the manager chose me to be
Lady Kant's personal concierge,
the reason is obvious.
If you only knew
how much we envy you in Lesan.
Me and all the girls at the hospital.
We all dream of a man like Walter Dorian.
One who takes us to live in the big city.
One who allows us to quit our jobs.
Elisabeth.
Hey, is everything all right?
I hardly ever see him.
He's always away.
Sometimes he comes home,
stays for a few hours,
and then leaves again.
- Oh God! Is he cheating on you?
- No!
It's his work.
He explained it to me.
What does he do?
Well...
I didn't really understand all that well.
Business, he says.
- But he earns a lot of money!
- Yes.
It's all right then!
You know what I say?
I'd swap with you in a second!
Come now,
you've got everything you could wish for:
a beautiful home,
a man who's never around...
What more could you ask for?
I want Walter!
I'm only happy when I'm with him.
Has anyone seen Roberto?
No, sir.
Where the hell is he?
Lady Kant is almost here!
May I be of assistance, sir?
No.
Ada! Have you seen Roberto?
- No, sir.
- I don't understand, he's not here...
- Good morning, sir.
- Roberto!
- Sorry for being late.
- Come quickly. Lady Kant is on her way.
Thank you.
- Lady Kant, I'm the hotel manager.
- Nice to meet you.
- Welcome to the Excelsior.
- Thank you.
You can check-in at the reception desk.
- How was your trip? Do you need anything?
- Not at the moment, thank you.
If you do need anything, just ask Roberto,
your personal concierge.
After you.
A latest model safe:
reinforced steel
with an ultra-silent mechanism.
Making it practically impossible
for anyone to identify the combination.
Wonderful.
Only the best for
a client such as yourself, Lady Kant.
Go ahead.
I'll send Roberto up at once
to prepare a bath for you.
Hello?
Yes. Put him through, please.
Giorgio.
Hi.
Yes, fine.
I'm just about to have a bath.
How are you?
Where will we see each other tonight?
Your place?
Are you sure? Wouldn't it be better...
I understand.
You're right, it might be inconvenient.
Fine, your house at half-past nine.
What's the address?
Yes...
Yes.
Great.
See you later, Giorgio.
And thanks for the invitation.
Lady Kant.
Your bath is ready.
- Thank you.
- Do you need anything else?
No.
Thank you, Roberto. You may go.
For anything at all, I'll be here
in the hotel until six o'clock.
Simply ring the bell.
- Goodbye.
- Keep the change.
- Thank you, ma'am. Goodnight.
Goodbye.
Walter!
Darling, you're here.
You're finally here.
Calm yourself.
Unfortunately,
I have to go out now, Elisabeth.
But you just got back.
- And you weren't at home.
- I know, you're right.
I'm sorry, forgive me!
Please don't go.
- Stay with me a while.
- I haven't got the time.
Let's at least eat together!
I'll cook something.
- I'll be quick!
- Elisabeth.
You know I don't like it
when you act like this.
Yes, I know.
Walter.
You'll come back later, won't you?
I'll be late. Don't wait up for me.
Are you trying to get me drunk?
Oh, come now,
you've only had a glass of wine.
And it's enough.
Thank you, Giorgio.
For a toast.
All right then.
To Eva...
the most beautiful woman in the world.
You're exaggerating.
For me you are!
Giorgio, please.
Forgive me.
It's just having you here, Eva,
is a dream come true.
A dream.
It's been a nice evening.
Don't ruin it.
Try to scream and I'll kill you.
You're wasting your time.
Diabolik.
What does that mean?
The Pink Diamond is fake.
Against the wall, move it.
It's a perfect copy.
Impossible for the human eye
to tell the difference.
Don't play games with me.
It'll cost you dearly.
I don't appreciate being called a liar.
Especially when I'm telling the truth.
You're not afraid of me.
I've had to deal with criminals
in the past.
And I've never been afraid.
Why should a woman as rich as Lady Kant
have a fake diamond?
I secretly sold the real one
when Lord Kant was still alive.
Why?
I needed the money.
Answer.
I was being blackmailed by
the Johannesburg mob.
I couldn't permit my husband to find out
certain things about my past.
Who has the diamond now?
I don't know.
I sold it through an intermediary,
but I don't know to whom.
A woman like you is capable of lying
without batting an eyelash.
It's easy to discover the truth.
Take the diamond and have it examined.
I will.
- But if you're lying...
- You'll come back to kill me.
Right?
Yes.
No one plays games with me and lives.
But if I'm telling the truth,
please give it back to me.
I'm invited to an important reception.
I want to wear it to be
the most beautiful.
The most admired.
You don't need a diamond for that.
Walter.
Why did you scream?
Oh God, I was so afraid!
- What's going on?
- Was that you outside?
Of course it was me. I just got back.
No, no, no...
At the end of the garden...
There...
There was...
Something rose up from the lawn
and then...
And then a man came out from
under the ground!
A man from under the ground?
Yes!
Does that sound possible?
But I saw him!
Where?
There!
By the bushes.
It's very dark over there.
How could you have seen anyone?
Well, I didn't... see him clearly.
It was more...
A shadow.
Yes!
It's full of shadows down there.
I think it's obvious you let
your imagination get the better of you.
Or am I supposed to believe
that you really saw...
a ghost come out of the ground?
You're right.
- Do you feel better now?
- Yes.
Good.
Let's go to bed
and forget about the whole thing.
Forget these ugly thoughts.
Roberto?
Can you come here a second, please?
Good morning, Lady Kant.
Good morning.
Thank you for breakfast.
Just doing my job.
Do you know Diabolik?
I've heard of him.
The same as everyone else, I imagine.
- But you've never met him?
- Luckily for me, no.
How can you be so certain,
if no one knows what he looks like?
Forgive me, Lady Kant,
I don't understand why
you're asking me all these questions.
Because I'd like to meet him.
You're not afraid of him?
No.
You understand that meeting Diabolik
means meeting death?
I'll take that risk.
As you wish.
But now I can no longer allow you to go.
I don't want to.
But I saw him.
I saw him.
I know I saw him.
I saw him!
Incredible.
With these masks you can become anyone.
Hold on.
The only people to know
that the ring was in the safe, were me,
the hotel manager...
and that inspector.
Ginko.
Of course!
That was you in the hotel in Bellair.
You completely fooled me.
What is it?
You're wondering if you can trust me.
You're the first person I've let see
my real face.
That was your decision.
Why did you do it?
You still don't know if you can trust me.
You know too much, I'm sorry.
Either I follow my heart and trust you,
or trust my logic and kill you.
At this point
I'd like to know more about you.
What's your name?
Walter Dorian.
But it's a false identity.
Who are you really?
I don't talk about that. Don't insist.
All right.
Let's change the subject.
Have you got a woman?
Hello, Police?
Do you love her?
I'll leave her some money
and disappear from her life.
What about you?
I'm engaged.
To whom?
Giorgio Caron.
The Deputy Minister of Justice?
What did you imagine was going to happen?
What are you talking about?
This evening,
as you were coming to my house.
What did you imagine was going to happen?
An evening with friends, nothing more.
Eva, you know well
that I'm in love with you.
You've known since we met in South Africa,
when your husband was still alive.
Don't talk nonsense.
Nonsense?
Then why,
when you found yourself in trouble,
did you come to me?
You hardly knew me.
And yet you understood
that this poor imbecile...
was in love with you,
and would've done anything to help you.
What do you want, Giorgio?
What any man in love would want.
To marry the woman he loves
and make her happy.
But I don't love you.
Do you love him?
I thought he was a friend.
But you loved Lord Kant, didn't you?
- You're becoming unpleasant.
- Answer me.
Did you marry that old man for love...
or convenience?
And to think, he was the intermediary
who sold the Pink Diamond for me.
A deputy minister doing deals
with the South African mob.
Lady Kant has no need to marry
a deputy minister.
What Lady Kant doesn't need
is an investigation into
a certain presumed hunting accident,
which left her widowed...
and wealthy.
You know well I asked for your help
to avoid having the Kant name
dragged through an investigation.
Perhaps, yes.
Fortunately, no one knew who Eva Kant was
before she became a lady.
What are you talking about?
Some people still remember you
at The Blue Horse.
The Blue Horse?
Yes.
Have you forgotten?
The night-club where you used to perform.
Peter Sorel.
Remember him?
He was a gangster.
And you worked for him.
Or should we talk about Protocol KD-26?
Industrial espionage is a crime.
You know that, don't you?
You made inquiries about me.
Naturally!
Did you imagine I would have helped you
without knowing who you were?
I have a file on you in my safe.
Why?
You didn't answer my question.
Do you love him?
I detest him.
Sit down.
On the 11th of next month,
it'll be one year
since your husband's death.
The next day, we'll throw a big party.
The kind you like: extravagant, lavish!
And we'll announce our engagement.
I'm waiting for you to say yes, Eva.
Yes.
Good.
I'll have a surprise for you
that'll leave you breathless.
You'll see.
I love you, Eva.
I love you.
I want you.
I want you now.
Now...
If I have to be your fiancée, I will.
But don't ever dare to touch me again!
I can't breathe!
It'll pass.
He's a coward.
I'll get that file.
For you.
So you can continue to be
the beautiful Lady Kant.
Hold on...
You've decided not to kill me.
So now you trust me?
I don't know you well enough
to be certain,
but I know I'll never meet
another woman like you.
What now?
- I'll take care of Caron.
- How?
I'll take his place.
Will you have to kill him?
Only if necessary.
Good morning, Miss Gay.
Inspector Ginko.
The severed head! Oh God!
Please, help me!
- Maris, take her inside.
- At once.
- Stay with her.
- Yes, sir.
Don't allow her out for any reason.
If necessary, give her a sedative.
Inspector, what came over her?
I don't know. But this could be it.
Clear the road.
Get all the cars out of sight.
Yes, sir.
As you are aware,
Mrs Eva Kant is a guest at your hotel.
She's my fiancée.
I'm entrusting her to your care.
I presume I don't need to add
anything else?
Ah, our engagement hasn't yet
been officially announced.
I'm relying on your discretion.
Eugenio.
- Is Roberto still with Lady Kant?
- As far as I am aware.
How is that possible?
He took her breakfast over an hour ago.
He's probably just
being the lady's man again, sir.
What's more,
if he's still in there, maybe Lady Kant...
Lady Kant what? Mind what you say!
I'm not saying anything!
But if I were you, I'd make sure...
Get back to work! Go!
- When will I see you again?
- As soon as I have the file.
- When will that be?
- Tomorrow.
- So soon?
- At midday.
Go to Bellavita Café.
A man will approach you and say:
"Lady Kant,
your eyes are the colour of emeralds."
It'll be me.
Are you making fun of me?
Why should I?
I know men like you.
They show up, take what they want,
make promises, then disappear.
What do you mean?
You may not come.
And I don't want to be
left waiting there like an idiot.
You don't know me: my word is my word.
I'll be there.
The wardrobe.
Coming.
Sorry for disturbing you, Lady Kant.
May I?
Please.
- Did you happen to see Roberto?
- Yes.
He was here earlier.
He brought me breakfast and then left.
That's strange,
reception told me he was still here.
- They were obviously mistaken.
- Yes, obviously.
Roberto may have left
a bunch of keys here.
By mistake, obviously.
Do you mind if I take a look?
- Be my guest.
- Thank you.
DO YOU KNOW MORSE CODE?
YES
COME OUT WHEN I TELL YOU
He must have left them elsewhere.
Since I'm here,
I might as well check the linen.
It'll only take a second.
- Of course.
- Most kind.
- Sir!
- Yes?
You forgot to look in the bathroom.
- Pardon?
- For the keys.
Roberto gave it a quick clean,
perhaps he left them there.
- Well, it's really not that important.
- But isn't that why you came?
Please, check.
You're right. I'll check.
Remember: tomorrow at midday.
Palmer.
Inspector!
Over here.
It's you.
The severed head.
Don't touch it, Florian!
Nobody touches a thing.
With Diabolik, you can never be sure.
Inspector, these faces are perfect.
What does Diabolik do with them?
We'll ask him.
POLICE
BUREAUCRATS
BANKERS
JEWELLERS
POLITICIANS
MINISTERS, DEPUTY MINISTERS,
UNDER-SECRETARIES
GIORGIO CARON
DEPUTY MINISTER
Car approaching.
Never mind, it looks like a family.
Roger that, the car didn't stop.
Good. Hold your positions.
Inspector, it's two in the morning.
Do you still think Diabolik will show up?
We're not moving from here, Palmer.
Even if we have to wait a year.
Inspector, another car's approaching.
Single male occupant.
Serra, can you see it?
No, the road's empty.
Impossible, he has to pass that way.
- Inspector, no one's coming.
- Then check it out!
- Quickly!
- I'm going.
Inspector, a hedge moved!
It's him! From now on radio silence.
Get ready.
One false move and I shoot.
Raise your hands.
Don't move.
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Freeze!
Damn!
Hands up.
Handcuffs.
Florian, the car.
Yes, sir.
- Miss!
- Let go of me!
- Miss, stop!
- Walter!
Walter.
I'll bring you the bill.
Miss.
Another tea?
Yes, thank you.
- Did you hear the news?
- What's happened?
Here, look for yourself!
Amazing!
He's been caught.
A great success for Inspector Ginko!
DIABOLIK ARRESTED!
It's him!
- The guillotine!
- Murderer!
Thief!
Hang him!
Monster!
Silence in the courtroom!
Today we begin a trial
that is destined go down in history.
The defendant, Mr Walter Dorian,
presuming that is his real name
as we have no paperwork to prove it,
is accused of being Diabolik,
the criminal
who has been terrorising Clerville.
A merciless thief and murderer,
who has committed crimes for which
no mitigating factors exist.
HOW CAN I HELP?
This court is now in session.
Your Honour, the accused has refused
the right to legal representation.
- Did he state that himself?
- No, he remains absolutely silent.
- He refuses to say a word, therefore...
- I understand.
Try to find him
the first available public defender.
HOW CAN I HELP?
- I request a psychiatric assessment
for my client. -Your Honour.
If I may remind my colleague,
the accused has already been assessed,
and declared fully aware of
his actions and their consequences.
Really?
By who?
The court psychiatrist.
Members of the jury, look!
He is unable to stop
his eyelids from blinking!
A clear sign of mental illness.
VIA DEI FABBRI
THIRD BRICK TO THE LEFT
Diabolik is a master of manipulation.
He's capable of tricking
and bending to his will
even those people above all suspicion.
No.
I never saw anything
that could have led me to understand.
He was the man I loved.
That's all I know.
THE ROAD TO PAPIGNAN 37KM
Your Honour, the fact that my client's
identity and nationality remain unknown
does not automatically mean
that he is the infamous Diabolik.
It is the public prosecutor's job
to prove this accusation.
Beyond any reasonable doubt!
Your Honour,
may I show some items to the court?
Proceed.
This outfit was found in
the cave under Villa Dorian.
And this rare photograph of Diabolik
was captured
by a security camera
during one of his robberies.
As you can see, the outfits are identical.
TAKE THE YELLOW AND GREEN VIALS
We now await tomorrow's verdict
in the case against Diabolik.
There doesn't appear to be much doubt
about what that verdict will be.
In the name of the people of Clerville,
this court declares the accused
guilty!
The death sentence will be carried out
at Ronson Prison the day after tomorrow.
And without doubt,
the moment the guillotine blade
drops on Diabolik,
the entire population of Clerville
will breathe a sigh of relief.
- I wish to speak with Mr Giorgio Caron.
- The Deputy Minister of Justice?
Precisely.
Here you go, lovely lady.
Fill out this form
and we'll let you know if and when
the Deputy Minister can see you.
Call him.
Tell him Lady Kant is here.
No calls, Flora,
I don't want to be disturbed.
Very well, Mr Caron.
I tried to call you at the hotel
numerous times.
You were never in.
Or else you pretended not to be.
I'm here now.
To apologise for
your exaggerated reaction, I hope.
We should both apologise, don't you think?
You want me to apologise to you?
Maybe you don't understand, Eva.
There's no way I'll accept your refusal.
Not a chance.
I swear to God...
if you do I'll destroy you.
Giorgio, Giorgio...
Still making threats?
Have you still not understood
that to conquer a woman like me
you have to do the exact opposite?
You have to make me dream.
If you think I'm not rich enough,
you're wrong.
I'm a very powerful man.
It's not a question of money.
Or power.
What is it then?
Emotions.
Make my heart jump.
Give me moments I'll remember
for the rest of my life.
That could make me fall in love.
I can give you anything you desire.
I don't think so.
At least not anymore.
What a shame.
Goodbye forever, Giorgio.
And if you want to denounce me...
go ahead.
No, wait!
- Wait! Give me another chance!
- It's too late.
It's not too late. I'm begging you.
Put me to the test.
I'm willing to do anything for you.
Is this today's paper?
Yes, why?
GUILLOTINE AWAITS DIABOLIK
Got it.
Seeing that you are
the Deputy Minister of Justice...
arrange for me to meet Diabolik tonight.
Meet Diabolik tonight?
Whatever for?
It says he's the greatest criminal
in the history of Clerville.
It would be extraordinary to meet him
the night before his execution.
To me, it sounds like madness.
Whereas blackmailing me was normal?
- What's that got to do with it?
- Forget it, Giorgio.
You just proved you're not prepared
to do anything for me.
Maybe you don't want to,
or maybe you're not powerful enough.
In any case, farewell.
Fine! Fine!
I'll let you meet him.
But not by yourself.
I'm coming with you.
Warden, this lady,
whose name I obviously cannot disclose,
is a Secret Service agent.
I understand.
What can I do for you, sir?
We have to interrogate Diabolik.
May I ask why?
We suspect him to have information
relevant to national security.
National security!
Yes, so...
Excuse me.
This meeting must remain
absolutely top secret.
Therefore, if there are any microphones,
switch them off.
All right.
I'll do as you say, but I tell you now...
in my opinion, this meeting is pointless.
- And why would that be?
- Sir...
as soon as the prisoner
was sentenced to death
he fell into a state
that I can only define as catatonic.
He doesn't eat or speak.
He doesn't react to stimuli.
I can only presume that he fell into
an extreme form of depression,
triggered by the awareness
of his imminent death.
Stand.
Walk.
Diabolik.
Diabolik!
Come on, do a trick for me.
Diabolik! Oh!
Hey!
- The warden's down there. Let's go.
- Start walking.
Diabolik! Get me out of here!
This way.
Sit.
Thank you, men. You can leave.
Sir, what I'm allowing you to do
is extremely informal in nature.
Please be quick.
This won't take long.
When you're done, bang on the door.
Close it! Close it!
Well?
How did it go?
You were right.
It was like talking to the wall.
At least we tried.
After you.
Stand up.
This way. Walk.
This way.
- Good morning, sir.
- Good morning.
Good morning, Mr Caron.
I've prepared your post.
I haven't got the time now, Flora.
I'll look at it later.
Inspector, in less than a minute
your battle with Diabolik will be over.
History will remember Diabolik
as the most feared criminal of all time.
What an incredible man.
His indifference is terrifying.
Even in the face of death,
he remains ice-cold.
Do you say so? I think he's afraid.
He's been that way for days.
Like he's been struck dumb.
That's true.
His gaze is dull, unresponsive.
As though he's on drugs.
No!
It's a mask!
It's Giorgio Caron!
The Deputy Minister of Justice
has been decapitated!
Sir,
what I'm allowing you to do
is extremely informal in nature.
Please be quick.
- This won't take long.
- When you're done, bang on the door.
Close it! Close it!
Eva...
Eva, the picklock.
The pentothal is starting to work.
Now he'll answer my questions.
Where do you keep your file on Eva Kant?
The safe in my office.
The combination?
Four, six, seven, eight.
We have to hurry.
Wait.
Is there anything precious in the safe?
The key to my treasure.
What treasure?
Jewels, diamonds,
gold ingots.
The fruit of my blackmail.
- I am a very...
- Silence.
What does the key open?
Safe deposit box 1325,
in the vault of the Central Bank of Ghenf.
Eva, the scopolamine.
Incredible.
I saw the Deputy Minister leave
the interrogation cell with my own eyes!
It wasn't enough just to escape;
he wants us to think him dead.
But you discovered the truth, Inspector.
And he doesn't know.
We have to take full advantage.
News of this mustn't get out.
But what'll we do
with Giorgio Caron's body?
Can you keep it here,
until tomorrow at least?
That's a decision
I'm not authorised to make.
But if you want, I'll ask.
We have to discover the identity
of the woman who helped him escape.
Until the news gets out,
she has no reason to go into hiding.
- From the warden's description,
she's not the type to go unnoticed. - No.
And Caron must have known her well
if he trusted her so much.
We'll talk to friends,
relations, colleagues.
- Maybe someone met her.
- How should I proceed?
We'll split up. Meanwhile send
two men to Caron's office and home.
Very well, Inspector.
- Florian!
- Sergeant.
Inspector, we've been given authorisation.
So we're in agreement:
officially, Diabolik is dead.
Very well.
TOP SECRET
Inspector Ginko, Clerville Police Force.
I need to talk to
Deputy Minister Caron's office.
Hello? Yes.
Inspector Ginko?
What does he want?
All right, put him through.
- Inspector, how can I help you?
- Hello, ma'am.
I need your help in a delicate matter
which requires the utmost discretion.
- I'll do what I can.
- We're looking for someone.
A woman, and we know
the Deputy Minister knows her.
You can ask him yourself, he's here.
- I'll put you through.
- No, wait!
Listen very carefully.
I'm sorry, Inspector, wait for what?
I don't understand.
Two of my men are on their way.
Leave the office calmly,
approach them and tell them
that Diabolik is there.
Diabolik? Where?
Do as I say, ma'am.
I'll explain everything later.
Speak only to my men. Understand?
All right, all right.
Sir?
Leaving already, sir?
Go quickly.
What happened?
I got the file, but it's pointless
trying to hide your past.
Why?
Ginko knows I'm alive.
It won't take him long
to find out who helped me.
Ma'am?
Are you here, ma'am?
Where is she?
Hey!
Ma'am!
Ma'am! Everything all right?
Where to now?
Ghenf.
Do you still plan on walking into the bank
disguised as Caron?
I can't.
And we won't be needing this anymore.
But I'm not giving up on the heist.
A blonde with her hair in a chignon?
That's Eva Kant.
Eva Kant.
- The heiress?
- Yes, that's her.
She was here just the other day.
What was her relationship to Mr Caron?
The Deputy Minister was in love with her.
Head-over-heels.
She took advantage of him, didn't she?
Tricked him.
So it seems.
Inspector, the safe doesn't show
signs of being forced.
How did Diabolik open it?
He clearly knew the combination.
We need to find out what he took.
Come with me, ma'am.
Check if anything's missing.
I'm not sure.
It was the Deputy Minister's safe.
As far as I know, he usually kept
work files and important documents in it.
Might he recently have put
something of considerable value in it?
Perhaps jewels,
or a significant amount of cash.
As far as I'm aware, no.
And if I may, it sounds strange to me.
Why?
The Deputy Minister held
a good position and led a nice life,
but he wasn't a wealthy man.
I understand.
Thank you, ma'am, you may go home.
But, please, the maximum discretion.
Don't tell anyone what has happened.
Mixon.
- Accompany the lady.
- This way, ma'am.
I can't go home.
I still have paperwork to finish.
Ma'am, we're sealing the office.
No one is allowed in here.
Thank you again, goodbye.
Goodbye.
Catalogue the contents of the safe.
As you wish, Inspector,
but it seems a waste of time to me.
- Diabolik will have taken what he wanted.
- No, Palmer, we can't be sure of that.
Come on, let's start the search.
Inspector!
Inspector, look what I found.
Hidden behind the radiator.
Look.
The transcript of a call
between Bolten the jeweler
and the South African Ambassador.
They're discussing some diamonds
illegally imported by the Ambassador.
There's even a tape.
Look.
Some photos of a man going into a hotel
with a girl no older than 20.
This is Guido Furlan, the industrialist.
Married with children.
From what I've seen,
it's all similar stuff.
What was Caron up to,
blackmailing all these people?
Perhaps.
He was definitely collecting dirt on them.
Maybe this is what Diabolik
was looking for but didn't find it.
I'm not convinced.
There's something...
Blackmail isn't his style.
CENTRAL BANK OF GHENF
- Mrs Morel?
- That's right.
Ada Fanel, the manager.
Hello and welcome.
It's my pleasure.
- We finally get to meet.
- Indeed.
Your precious paintings?
- In the car.
- There they are! Chop-chop!
Their story is a romantic one,
but ever so sad.
A young and very talented painter
without a penny to his name,
and a beautiful high society girl.
Her family opposes their love
and forces them to split up.
- It sounds like a novel.
- And yet it's a true story.
- In you go, boys.
- A true story.
- After you.
- Thank you.
Open up, please, Gianluca.
And that beautiful girl was
my grandmother.
Goodness! Then your grandmother
and the great Tournier...
Yes! That's right.
And as a parting gift,
he painted these two portraits of her.
Without wishing to state the obvious,
today they must be worth a fortune.
Yes, but I don't care about money.
That's what insurance is for!
But these two paintings are of
immense emotional importance to me.
Truly immense!
- Just the thought of them being stolen...
- Don't worry, that won't happen.
Our security system is
absolutely foolproof, I assure you.
Its genius lies in its simplicity.
The vault was hollowed out
from one enormous block of steel.
The ceiling, the floor, the four walls,
all reinforced steel.
Impressive!
Between the steel walls
and exterior walls,
there is a cavity with a wire cage
surrounding the entire vault.
If anyone even touches it,
never mind tries to cut it,
an alarm goes off,
and the police would be here
in five minutes.
So, if I've understood correctly,
it's like a three-layer cake.
With exterior walls,
a wire cage and the steel vault, right?
My word!
Nobody's ever getting in here!
Exactly. Here we are.
Number 1962.
- This is your key.
- Thank you.
First, I insert mine,
then you insert yours.
- Like this?
- Like that.
Three, two, one...
There. Proceed.
Where did you get them?
In Giorgio Caron's office.
Hidden behind the toilet radiator.
That rat.
- Was he blackmailing you?
- Yes.
He wanted one million in gold ingots
for the photos.
I was ready to pay him.
Well, that's no longer necessary.
Here.
Thank you, Inspector, thank you.
You're a true gentleman.
Goodbye.
He asked one for gold ingots,
another for jewels...
Caron must have a treasure
hidden away someplace.
Now I understand why the autopsy found
traces of those two drugs in his body.
The scopolamine was obvious,
to deprive him of his will power.
Allowing us to take him to the gallows
without any resistance.
The pentothal was to get him to reveal
where his treasure is hidden.
We need to find out, too.
Before Diabolik pulls off the heist.
It's the only way we'll catch him.
Easier said than done, Inspector.
We searched his home and office.
Interrogated everyone there is
to interrogate, but no one knows a thing.
Caron was clever, I'll give him that.
Without raising suspicion,
he blackmailed his way up the ladder
and accumulated a fortune
that's proving hard to track down.
Gold, diamonds... but never money.
Clever but also an idiot.
With a safe at his disposal he went
and hid those files behind a radiator.
Even the cleaning lady
could have found them.
Have the seals removed
from Caron's office.
Why?
Because you're right.
It doesn't make any sense to keep such
compromising documents behind a radiator.
Do you think someone
put them there on purpose?
Exactly.
Someone who knew
we would've looked in the safe.
These masks are amazing.
How did it go?
The paintings are in
safe deposit box number 1962.
Good work.
It was easy.
What now?
The bank shuts at five.
- Goodbye, ma'am.
- See you tomorrow, Aldo.
Only two security guards remain inside.
Everyone's out.
At approximately ten-past five
the guards activate the alarm
and turn off the lights.
The lasers will activate
at twenty past five.
They will shut off after five hours,
37 minutes and 21 seconds.
The residual heat will melt through
the final millimetres of steel.
But if it melts just one second early,
mightn't the laser hit the wire cage?
That won't happen.
How can you say that with such certainty?
I don't say it. Physics does.
Relax, you've done your part.
It's my turn now.
- Some tea?
- Thanks, leave it there.
It's a map of the water system
that runs under the bank.
It shows all the manholes.
See number 25?
Uh-huh.
I enter and exit through there.
You'll have to make your way along
a completely straight section of tunnel.
No one will be down there at night.
And if someone is?
All the worse for him.
In any case, the cistern isn't far.
Once inside,
I can work without complications.
How is it possible
that nothing worries you?
A lot of things worry me.
But for every problem,
I try to find the right solution.
This, for example,
will resolve the problem of the wall.
I just have to make sure I stop
before I touch the cage.
This is more straightforward.
I just have to prolong it
and pass it through the wire cage,
making sure not to touch it.
A few drops of acid will do
to melt the lock on the safe deposit door.
Have you calculated how long
it'll take to flood the vault?
The flow of water is
5,000 litres per minute.
The volume of the cistern and vault
is 700 cubic metres.
- It'll take two and a half hours.
- Doesn't that worry you?
Trapped in there for two and a half hours
without knowing what's going on outside.
You're wrong.
I know exactly
what'll be happening outside.
There isn't anything
I haven't taken into consideration.
Good evening, ma'am.
Were you looking for this?
No, Inspector, there must be
some kind of misunderstanding.
Don't lie to me, ma'am.
We caught you with your hands
behind the radiator.
I don't know why you acted so foolishly,
but it's obvious that you know
many of your boss's secrets.
Whether you are also his accomplice
remains to be seen.
I'm nobody's accomplice!
Search my house, check my bank account.
- I never took anything!
- Blackmail is a crime.
You knew about it, but didn't report it.
How could I? I'm his secretary.
Besides, it would've been my word
against the Deputy Minister's.
You removed this from the safe
so that we wouldn't find it.
Yes... Yes, I'm sorry.
I panicked, I was afraid of
getting dragged into it.
I was stupid. Really stupid.
What else is missing from the safe?
You know, don't you?
You know what Diabolik took.
I don't know if he took anything else,
but of one thing I'm sure: a key.
A key to what?
I don't understand why you refuse my help.
You're not ready yet.
I'm not ready?
Sorry for reminding you,
but if you still have your head
it's thanks to me.
I've planned for every eventuality,
I don't need anyone's help.
What's my role supposed to be?
The good wife who waits for you at home?
What if the police chase you?
Only one policeman
can cause me any trouble.
That's Ginko.
But right now, he's in Clerville.
- Damn witch!
- Contain yourself, Palmer.
Contain myself? How, Inspector?
If only she'd told us earlier
that Diabolik had taken the key
to a safe deposit box
in the Central Bank of Ghenf!
- She's made us lose days on him!
- We're still in time.
If Diabolik had pulled off the heist,
we would've heard by now.
You're right, Inspector, as always.
- What are you doing?
- Calling the bank.
The security guards will still be inside,
we have to warn them.
Palmer, haven't you understood yet?
Diabolik is capable
of taking anyone's place.
It could be him answering the phone!
- What about warning the Ghenf Police?
- Everyone stays in the dark.
- He can't discover that we know.
- So what are we going to do?
Put a team together, we're going to Ghenf.
When the alarm sounds,
the guards will check the monitors
and think...
There's a leak, the vault's flooding!
And they'll deactivate the alarm.
- Will I turn off the alarm?
- Yes.
Hello?
What?! Sweet Jesus!
Call the fire brigade, at once!
I'll be there as soon as I can.
The fire brigade will arrive
after at most 15 to 20 minutes.
Lord above, this is a leak
of biblical proportions!
A pipe must have burst
in the toilet located inside the vault.
Do you reckon?
It seems a tad excessive for a toilet!
But it can't be coming from outside.
The vault is completely sealed.
Solid steel, one metre thick.
It's impossible.
In any case, we'll have to get a move on.
At this rate, the water level will be
above the vault door within the hour.
We won't be able to open it
without flooding the bank.
Don't worry,
the manager will soon be here.
The only person able to open
the vault door at night is the manager.
But I've made sure
she won't get there in time.
The final problem is the monitors.
But the water will take care of them.
Lord above!
The water must have reached
the fuse box inside the vault
and short-circuited the cameras.
With the cameras out of commission
I can enter without being seen.
I'll have all the time I need
to force open the safe deposit box,
without raising any suspicions.
Inspector Ginko, Clerville Police Force.
What's going on?
Logan, Fire Chief.
An accident, Inspector.
The bank's vault has flooded.
- Are you the night watchmen?
- Yes, Inspector.
- Why aren't you in front of the monitors?
- The cameras short-circuited.
Inspector, my men and I
are going down into the tunnels.
- No, it could be dangerous.
- Dangerous, in what way?
You could meet Diabolik.
Lord above!
But, Inspector, Diabolik's dead!
That's what we let people believe
in order to catch him.
This is his work.
He's emptying the vault.
- Get me the Ghenf Police.
- At once.
This is Ghenf Central.
Send all available men
to the Central Bank, now!
She's here!
You're finally here, ma'am.
Diabolik isn't dead,
he's emptying the vault!
Sweet Jesus!
Diabolik is inside here.
You need to get that into your heads!
Inspector, if we open this door,
the whole bank will be flooded.
- We can't have that!
- We'll pay for the damage, all right?
- Inspector, there's another problem.
- Which is?
Whoever opens this door
will be hit by a wave of such magnitude,
that they risk serious injury,
or even death!
- Precisely!
- All right.
Then get me a map
of the water tunnels in this area,
with all the manholes indicated.
Can you do that?
Certainly, sir.
Good wife, my ass!
This is my city and these are my men,
don't tell me what to do!
Inspector Driskell,
if you send your men into the tunnels,
Diabolik will kill them
before they even realise what's going on.
Unlike you, I'm not afraid of Diabolik.
We have him trapped, he can't escape.
As you wish.
But be prepared to count the bodies.
And what do you suggest?
Diabolik doesn't know we're here.
We wait for him to resurface.
This is a map of the water system
around the bank.
Diabolik has to come out
through one of these manholes.
- Do you want them all watched?
- Yes.
Two men at every manhole, ready to shoot.
And place roadblocks on all access routes.
Agreed.
- Florian.
- Inspector.
Take a man and watch the seafront.
Remember, absolutely no one gets by.
- Excuse me, Officer...
- I'm sorry, miss, you can't pass.
- You'll have to turn back.
- Hold on, that's Eva Kant!
It was an honour to watch you at work,
Inspector Ginko.
Men!
Let's roll!
Ginko.
- Driskell here, who's this?
- Dalton, Inspector.
We've a broken streetlamp here.
You don't say!
While you're at it, make sure nobody
has dropped any rubbish on the ground!
What's going on, Driskell?
Nothing, one of my men says
there's a broken streetlamp.
Let me talk to him.
This is Ginko. What's your location?
On the wharf, to the left of the bank.
Hold your position, I'll be right there.
Palmer, you stay here.
- I'll come with you, Inspector.
- I said stay here.
What's the problem, Inspector?
Streetlamps get broken!
Or someone wants it not to be lit!
- Do you think it was Diabolik?
- I don't know.
But I'd better take a look.
You're in charge while I check it out.
Did you hear that?
Hey!
Freeze!
The mask.
It's over.
You wouldn't shoot an unarmed man.
You're right.
I'm not a killer like you.
No, you let the guillotine
do your dirty work.
I don't like it, but that's the law.
Your law.
Everyone's.
Every citizen, every human being.
Not mine.
And that's your downfall.
You're destined to fail
because you're alone.
Don't move!
That's where you're wrong, Inspector.
I'm not alone.
Now I've got Eva.
Start the motor.
Bastard.
I'll get you.
Inspector!
Have you decided what to wear tonight?
Not yet.
What do you suggest?
Something that goes with this.
Why should I wear a fake diamond?
Because it's not fake.
Where did you get it?
It was in Caron's safe deposit box.
Now I understand.
The surprise that would've
left me breathless.
He bought it back.
That worm.
Why?
It belongs at the bottom of the sea.
It represented my past.
Now I've got you.
THE END
This film is loosely based on
Diabolik No. 3 "THE KING OF TERROR"
by Angela and Luciana Giussani
and
"THE KING OF TERROR-THE REMAKE"
by Mario Gomboli and Tito Faraci